decisionanalyst.com 2019-12-12

# Privacy Policy

### Privacy Policy

Effective Date: December 10, 2018

Who We Are  
Decision Analyst, Inc. and its U.S. subsidiaries, Nuance Coding and Symmetric Sampling (collectively, “Decision Analyst” or “we”) are committed to respecting your privacy. The site www.DecisionAnalyst.com is owned and operated by Decision Analyst, Inc.

Decision Analyst Subsidiaries: [Symmetric Sampling](https://www.symmetricsampling.com/) and [Nuance Coding](http://www.nuancecoding.com/index.html).

Panel Sites: [American Consumer Opinion](https://www.acop.com/); [The Technology Advisory Board](https://www.technologyboard.com/); [The Physicians Advisory Council](https://www.physicianscouncil.com/); [The Medical Advisory Board](https://www.medicaladvisoryboard.com/); [The Contractor Advisory Board](https://www.contractorboard.com/); [The Executive Advisory Board](https://www.executiveadvisoryboard.com/); and Imaginators.

We believe that consumers have an inalienable right to privacy. We protect your privacy and anonymity by adhering to these standards:

  * [EU-US Privacy Shield and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Framework for the transfer of EU and Swiss data into the US](https://www.privacyshield.gov/)
  * In Compliance with [European Union General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR)](https://ec.europa.eu/commission/priorities/justice-and-fundamental-rights/data-protection/2018-reform-eu-data-protection-rules_en) created and enacted by the European Parliament and European Council.
  * [Children's Online Privacy Protection Rule](https://www.ftc.gov/enforcement/rules/rulemaking-regulatory-reform-proceedings/childrens-online-privacy-protection-rule) issued by the Federal Trade Commission (FTC).

Organizations We Belong To  
The www.DecisionAnalyst.com website is owned and operated by Decision Analyst, Inc., a leading international marketing research and marketing consulting company in the United States, located in the Dallas-Fort Worth area. We subscribe to the privacy, confidentiality, and ethics policies of these professional marketing and marketing research organizations:

EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework  
Decision Analyst complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States, respectively. Decision Analyst has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles of Notice, Choice, Accountability for Onward Transfer, Security, Data Integrity and Purpose Limitation, Access, and Recourse, Enforcement and Liability. If there is any conflict between the terms in the privacy policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield program, and to view our certification, please visit <https://www.privacyshield.gov/>.

Decision Analyst is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the FTC.

Pursuant to the Privacy Shield Frameworks, we acknowledge the following:

  * EU and Swiss individuals whose data is transferred into the United States have the right to access that data and to update, correct or amend it. Individuals wishing to exercise this right may do so by logging into your Panel Member Account.
  * We remain liable for the onward transfer of personal data to third parties unless we can prove that we were not a party to the actions giving rise to the damages.
  * We may be required to release personal information in response to lawful requests by legal authorities including to meet national security and law enforcement requirements.
  * Decision Analyst does not share, rent, or sell any personal data or permit its usage for reasons other than that for which it was originally provided. If this practice should change in the future, we will update this policy accordingly and provide individuals with opt-out or opt-in choice, as appropriate.

In compliance with the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Principles, Decision Analyst commits to resolve complaints about your privacy and our collection or use of your personal information. European Union or Swiss individuals with inquiries or complaints regarding this privacy should first contact Decision Analyst at:

Internet Operations Department  
Decision Analyst, Inc.  
604 Avenue H East  
Arlington, Texas 76011  
Phone numbers:  
Within the U.S., 1-817-649-5241  
International, 1-817-640-6166  
Email: [privacy@decisionanalyst.com](mailto:privacy@decisionanalyst.com)

Decision Analyst as further committed to refer unresolved privacy complaints under the EU-US and Swiss-US Privacy Shield Principles to an independent dispute resolution mechanism, the BBB EU PRIVACY SHIELD, operated by the Council of Better Business Bureaus. If you do not receive timely acknowledgement of your complaint, or if your complaint is not satisfactorily addressed, please visit [http://www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers](https://www.bbb.org/EU-privacy-shield/for-eu-consumers) for more information and to file a complaint.

Please note that if your complaint is not resolved through these channels, under limited circumstances, a binding arbitration option may be available before a Privacy Shield Panel.

GDPR For EU Individuals  
We comply with European Union General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) created and enacted by the European Parliament and European Council. EU individuals who have a grievance regarding Decision Analyst’s handling of their personal data have the right to pursue complaints directly with the appropriate Data Protection Authority (DPA). Please go to <https://ec.europa.eu/justice/article-29/structure/data-protection-authorities/index_en.htm> to find your local DPA.

Back to top

Information We Collect From You  
The only information that we collect from you is the information you voluntarily give to us when you either download STATS™ 2.0 Statistical Software and ChoiceModelR™ Software or your register for our double opt-in email list.

  * When you download STATS™ 2.0 Statistical Software and ChoiceModelR™ Software you are asked to provide the following information: your name, company name, company title, company phone number, mailing address, and email address.
  * When you sign-up for our email list you are only asked to provide your email address, name and company name.
  * When you fill out the Research Advice form and the Contact Us form, we collect name, company name, email and phone number, and a comment/question from you. This information is emailed to [Jerry W. Thomas](mailto:jthomas@decisionanalyst.com).

Back to top

How We Use Your Information  
In no event will we use your personal data other than for the purposes below.  
We use the information you provide to us while downloading our marketing research software to:

  * To measure the effectiveness of our advertising
  * To update you of any changes in STATS™ 2.0 Statistical Software and ChoiceModelR™ Software
  * To respond to an inquiry or request for information
  * To thank you for contacting Decision Analyst
  * To send you information about Decision Analyst products and services that we think might interest you.
  * To communicate with you regarding customer service related issues

We use the information you provide to us in the opt-in email list:

  * To measure the effectiveness of our advertising.
  * To update you of any changes or updates to our websites such as: new blog posts, articles, case studies, or to invite you to a Insider Series Webinar.
  * To respond to an inquiry or request for information
  * To thank you for contacting Decision Analyst.
  * To send you information about Decision Analyst products and services that we think might interest you.
  * To send you information about Decision Analyst webinars that we think might interest you.
  * To communicate with you regarding customer service related issues.

Back to top

How You Control Your Information  
You may unsubscribe from of Decision Analyst's email list at any time. If you would like to stop receiving Decision Analyst's brochures, articles, webinar invitations please contact **Cristi Allen** by emailing her at [callen@decisionanalyst.com](mailto:callen@decisionanalyst.com#Mailing%20List%20Removal) or calling at 1-817-640-6166.

Back to top

We Do Not Share Your Information  
Decision Analyst may contract with an email service provider to help us send our email newsletters and company announcements. In such cases, we will have a nondisclosure agreement with the email service provider to ensure your personal contact information is protected and private. Decision Analyst does not sell or rent the information you give us.

Back to top

How We Secure Your Information  
Decision Analyst has multiple security measures in place to ensure the confidentiality and protection of your personal information. The data is stored behind Decision Analyst's firewall, and the data is encrypted. We have security measures in place to protect against the loss, misuse, or alteration of any information we receive from you. As with any transmission over the Internet, there is some element of risk involved in sending personal information. To minimize this risk, we encrypt all information using the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol.

Back to top

Use Of Internet Technology (“Cookies” And Log Files)

  * “Cookies” are pieces of information that a website transfers to your computer's hard drive for record-keeping purposes. Cookies are used by thousands of websites to make your life as a web user much easier. Decision Analyst uses third party tracking cookies, from vendors such as Google, to track anonymous traffic data. The use of cookies is so we can track advertising results. Also, we may use use cookies for American Consumer Opinion® website. For example in the Affiliate Program, we may use cookies to track registrations back to any affiliate site that may have referred American Consumer Opinion® panel members, and we may use cookies to track other advertising efforts for American Consumer Opinion®. Some of this tracking is routed through the  www.decisionanalyst.com website.
  * Decision Analyst gathers information in our log files such as Internet Protocol (IP) address, browser type, Internet Service Provider (ISP), type of computing device, referring and exit pages, platform type, date and time stamp, number of clicks while onsite, and other variables.
  * Log-file information is not linked to any personally identifiable information and is used only to administer our systems, to make improvements to our website, and to determine the success of advertising campaigns.

Third Party Vendors  
Decision Analyst uses third party vendors, including Google, Microsoft AdCenter, to show ads on other websites on the Internet. Some of these vendors, including Google use cookies to serve ads based on a user’s prior visits to our website. Users may opt out of Google’s used of cookies by visiting the [Google Adverting Opt-Out Page](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/ads/) or the [Network Advertising Initiative Opt-Out Page](http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/).

Back to top

Links To Outside Sites  
The www.decisionanalyst.com website contains links to other websites. While these websites might be of interest to you, please note that their privacy policies may differ from ours. We encourage you to read the privacy statement of each site you visit.

Back to top

Legal Disclaimer  
If required by a court of law or government agency, your personal data might need to be disclosed, if we have a good-faith belief that such action is necessary to comply with a current judicial proceeding, a court order, or a legal process. We will take legal action, if appropriate, to protect your personal data. We will attempt to notify you in advance so that you can take legal action on your own, if desired, to protect your personal information.

Back to top

Enforcement Of Privacy Policy  
If you believe Decision Analyst, Inc. has violated this Privacy Policy with respect to your personal information, please contact us so that we can investigate and correct any errors or mistakes. If you are a US resident and you are not satisfied with our response, you may file a complaint with the Insights Association, 170 North Country Road, Suite 4, New York 11777.

Back to top

Questions and Comments  
We welcome your questions or comments regarding our data-protection practices and our Privacy Policy. If you have questions or concerns, please contact:

Internet Operations Department  
Decision Analyst, Inc.  
604 Avenue H East  
Arlington, Texas 76011  
Phone numbers:  
Within the U.S., 1-817-649-5241  
International, 1-817-640-6166  
Email: [privacy@decisionanalyst.com](mailto:privacy@decisionanalyst.com?Subject=Question%20Regarding%20DAI%20Corporate%20Site%20Privacy%20Policy)

This Privacy Policy is reviewed and updated annually.
